<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>
    <properties>
        <title>MetaData Extensions</title>
        <author email="peter at apache.org">Peter Donald</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="MetaData Extensions">
            <p>
                A container may support features beyond and above standard DNA
                lifecycle processing. These container extensions are given an
                identifier and this allows components to refer to specific
                extensions and
                <a href="model.html#dna.extension">declare</a>
                their compatibility with the extension.
            </p>
            <subsection name="Naming">
                <p>
                    Extension names are usually derived from the names of the
                    extra JavaDoc tags (or MetaClass Attributes) that they
                    support. For example, a container that supports the
                    "sec.role" (Security Role) JavaDoc tag implements the
                    container extension "sec". Alternatively the container may
                    support extensions such as "sec.auth" which indicates they
                    support a superset or subset of the "sec" tag.
                </p>
                <p>
                    If a particular container extension or feature does not
                    interpret specific tags or touches multiple tags then it is
                    recomended that the short name of the container be used to
                    name the feature (ie "plexus" or "plexus.aspect") to
                    indicate a plexus specific "aspect" container extension.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Once a name has been found for a partciular extension it
                    should be documented and listed in the extension registry
                    (unless it is container specific). No other extension may
                    be defined with the same name.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section name="Extension Development">
            <p>
                The development of container extension essentially can be
                broken down into two parts. Documenting and designing the
                metadata a component has to expose for container extension
                and implementing the container extension. The implementation
                of container extensions is beyond the scope of this document.
            </p>
            <p>
                When the metadata requirements for the container extension are
                being developed then it is useful to be able to name a
                particular extension so that components can declare
                compatibility with the extension.
            </p>
            <p>
                In this scenario it is best to use an extension name that
                clearly indicates the extension is under development. It is
                recomended that a prefix be added to the extension name with
                that prefix either being "x-" or the short name of the
                container. For example if JMX extensions were being developed
                for the Loom container the extension could be named either
                "x-mx" or "loom.mx"
            </p>
            <p>
                After the extension has matured and been completed then the
                developer should remove the the prefix and add the extension
                name and a description of the extension to the registry. 
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
