<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

    <properties>
        <title>DNA Release 1.1</title>
        <author>Peter Donald</author>
        <author>Mauro Talevi</author>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Introduction">
            <p>
                This is the second release of DNA. This release
                introduces several bug fixes and feature enhancements.
                The primary purpose of this release is the introduction
                of a high level User Guide. 
          	</p>
        </section>
        <section name="Changes">
            <ul>
                <li>
                	DNA packages renamed to org.codehaus.dna, following the
                	promotion of DNA to a top-level Codehaus project.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Fixed a bug in SAXConfigurationHandler that could cause a
                    ArrayStoreException using some parsers. Some parsers would
                    not pass the ContentHandler text content if it would be
                    removed during normalization of the XML document. The DNA
                    code did not expect this behaviour but has since been fixed
                    and unit test added to avoid regression.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Make it possible for users to subclass SAXConfigurationHandler
                    and overide processValueText() and processAttributeText() to
                    process text attributes prior to them being set. Added unit
                    tests to verify operation.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Add ConfigurationUtil.equals( config1, config2 ) utility
                    method that tests equality of two configurations and added
                    unit tests to verify functionality.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Support passing a PrintStream object into constructor of
                    ConsoleLogger to specify where the output is output.
                </li>
                <li>
                    MetaClass metadata annotations introduced. This makes it
                    possible to annotate a Java source file with JavaDoc tags
                    and generate a MetaClass descriptor from annotations. See
                    docs/metadata/index.html or
                    <a href="http://dna.codehaus.org/metadata">http://dna.codehaus.org/metadata</a>
                    for detailed description of new DNA metadata model.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Create a new dna-tools jar that contains tools to help
                    creating DNA components. Initially the jar includes tools
                    to generate metadata descriptors and validate DNA
                    components.  The tools jars is also packaged as a Maven
                    plugin, following the usual Maven name convention maven-dna-plugin.
                </li>
                <li>
                    Parameters, DefaultParameters and Parameterizable have
                    been removed from the DNA framework in the quest for
                    a simpler framework. 
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </body>

</document>
